Daniel Paul O'Dea

Dear Sir or Madam:

I am writing in response to your job posting for a User Experience Designer. After reading your job description, I am confident that my skills and my passion for research, design, and technology are a perfect match for this position.

I would bring to your company a broad range of skills, including:

- Strong knowledge of UX design and prototyping software including Sketch, InVision, and Adobe Creative Suite.
- Twenty years of Iterative Design Experience through lesson design, testing, and revision as an educator in the public schools and in private music instruction.
- Extensive leadership and teamwork skills developed through collaborating with teams of educators, leading daily class meetings, owning and operating a music school, leading and collaborating with a band of musicians, and booking the musical talent for a major festival.
- Deep understanding of the product life cycle through the production and distribution of two musical albums, both currently available at digital and physical retailers. Responsibilities included concept development and planning; performing, recording, editing, and audio production; graphic design and layout of all artwork for packaging and promotional materials; release for distribution and sale; procurement of airplay on terrestrial and digital radio; production of promotional videos; ongoing engagement in paid and grassroots social media campaigns; use of analytical tools to assess return-on-investment for various marketing platforms.
- Experience and continued learning in Front-End Web Development and UI design, including knowledge of Foundation and Bootstrap.

I would welcome the opportunity to further discuss this position with you. If you have questions or would like to schedule an interview, please contact me by phone at 732-319-9379 or by email at dansbands@hotmail.com. An example of my work can be found at danodeamedia.com/portfolio. I have enclosed my resume for your review, and I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely,

Daniel P. O'Dea

For O'Fea

Daniel Paul O'Dea

632 Eagle Rock Ave., West Orange, NJ 07052 | 732-319-9379 | dansbands@hotmail.com | danodeamedia.com

Objective

To secure a position in User Experience Design, an exciting field that combines three areas about which I am quite passionate: the creativity of making visual designs that excel in both form and function, the design thinking skills I developed from my former careers in music and education, and the development of human solutions through the synthesis of research and technology.

Skills

- Strong knowledge of major UX software suites including Sketch, InVision, Photoshop, and Illustrator
- Teamwork and leadership skills developed through collaborating with other educators and musicians, leading bands, and operating a private music school
- Front-end web development experience with HTML and CSS including **Bootstrap** and **Foundation**. Continuing a course of study that includes JavaScript, JQuery, and AngularJS.
- Fluency in productivity tools such as Microsoft Office and Google Drive, to more specialized applications, such
 as Logic Pro X and Cubase audio production suites, Adobe Premiere video production suite, Finale and Sibelius
 sheet music creators.
- Wide ranging experience with social media platforms such as **Facebook**, **Twitter**, and **Instagram**, including their implementation in the business setting, specifically use of analytics data, and knowledge of best practices for reaching a desired audience. Knowledge of computer hardware, software installation and troubeshooting, as well as mobile device integration.

Professional Experience

Owner, Dan's Music Studio - music lessons and recording services

6/2007-Present

- Management of a staff of twenty educators and office personnel.
- Oversight of curriculum, materials, facilities, and classroom equipment
- Delivery of individual instruction of students on ten different instruments
- Coordination of recitals including stage direction, scheduling, program book design, and operation of live sound reinforcement equipment
- Website design and management of social media/ marketing presence
- Multimedia production and design services for a variety of musical artists
- Began teaching individual lessons in 1997

Music Director, 43rd Annual New Jersey Folk Festival

1/2006-Present

- Curating, booking, and coordinating a diverse lineup of traditional folk music performers for multiple stage locations at this large festival; average annual attendance - 18,000 people
- Scheduling multiple stages, collecting artist materials, and disseminating this information to the 18 person committee responsible for the implementation of this massive event

Prior to becoming Music Director in 2014, I served as Director of the Jamming segment, a hybrid of stage
performance and community outreach, incorporating various community organizations (2007-2014), and
Graphics Coordinator (2006)

Teacher of String Orchestra, Edison Middle School, West Orange, NJ

9/2007-7/2015

- Managing four orchestras -160 students annually, including all instruction, maintenance and care of instruments, inventory management of school instruments, supplies, and sheet music
- Development and implementation of digital instructional tools for supplemental education, both in the classroom and at home; incorporation of mobile devices, SMART Board, SharePoint, Sibelius Scorch, and SmartMusic software.
- Iterative Lesson Design, including testing, implementation, and ongoing revision of methodologies through a tensection course cycle over a seven-year period. Each lesson was presented ten times in each 2-day cycle, being revised and adjusted to the user after each session. This process was repeated for each of the seven years, totaling seventy rounds of user testing per lesson

Band Leader, Dan O'Dea & Eagle Ridge

3/2008-Present

- Coordination of musical performances with groups ranging from solo to quintet
- Arranging, production, graphic design, web design, marketing; digital and physical sales of two albums: Eagle Ridge (2010), and Old Favorites (2016)
- Booking of 150 dates annually, and maintenance of relationships with venue management throughout performances, to ensure the best experience for venue guests
- Setup and operation of live sound and lighting equipment
- Performed with or opened for major artists such as Pete Seeger, Clarence Clemmons (E Street Band), Dicky Betts (Allman Brothers Band), Levon Helm (The Band, Bob Dylan), John McEuen (Nitty Gritty Dirt Band)

Education

General Assembly February 2017

Certificate - User Experience Design

Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

June 2007

Bachelor of Arts in Music, Minor - American Studies

- Concertmaster Rutgers University Salsa Band
- Graphics Coordinator New Jersey Folk Festival, 2006

West Orange High School

June 1997

- Concertmaster School Orchestra
- Co-Captain Varsity Wrestling Team
- Eagle Scout Boy Scouts of America